A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 6262-9286 FA739C
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Observations on the ministry of agriculture - Jordan Valley Commission Linear Programming Project (Reports 008283), 1973 (Box 351)
  Agriculture -- Research -- Jordan; Environmental policy -- Jordan; Gotsch, Carl; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- ICARDA International Center for Agricultural Research in the Dry Areas: a preliminary view (Reports 008284), 1975 (Box 351)
  Agriculture -- Research; Food crops -- Research; Russell, M. B.
- Rice production in South East Asia (Reports 008285), 1974 (Box 351)
  International Division/Middle East and Africa;Asia and the Pacific
  Rice production -- Asia, Southeastern; Wimberly, James E.
- Wheat and barley (Reports 008286), undated (Box 351)
  Wheat and barley improvement; Saari, E. E. (Eugene Eino); Srivastava, Jitendra, 1940-
- The Police Foundation: An assessment of the last five years and a look to the future (Reports 008287), 1983 (Box 352)
  Criminal Justice, Administration of -- United States; Police -- United States; Crime prevention -- United States -- Research; Police regulations -- United States -- Research; Police administration -- United States; Grinker, William J.; WJG Associates; Police Foundation (U.S.)
- Group dynamics in a North-Indian village: a study of factions (Reports 008288), 1954 (Box 352)
  05500087
  Rural development -- India; Lewis, Oscar, 1914-1970
- Report to Southern Languages Book Trust on accountancy methods (Reports 008289), 1956 (Box 352)
  Consultancy assignment was to study the current accountancy methods used by the South Indian publishing industry and to suggest improvements and to study the costing of books in order to help in determining cost factors for the Trust's loan program to pub
  Overseas Division;Asia/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  05500205
  The Southern Languages Book Trust
  Publishers and publishing -- Accounting -- India; Schulman, Jack.; Southern Languages Book Trust
- Southern Languages Book Trust: final report (Reports 008290), 1961 (Box 352)
  Publishers and publishing -- India; Roche, Edwin.; Southern Languages Book Trust (Madras, India)
- Report to Southern Languages Book Trust concerning the marketing of popular books in South India (Reports 008291), 1956 (Box 352)
  Working outline and list of specific objectives for planning for book marketing in India.
  Books -- Marketing -- India; Levin, Martin; Southern Languages Book Trust (Madras, India)
- Evaluation of Southwest Leadership Program, Center for Community Change (Reports 008292), 1977 (Box 352)
  07500361
  Community development -- New Mexico; Lacey, Richard A.; Southwest Leadership Program
- Staffing and functions of the educational planning unit in Ghana: Report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 008293), 1968 (Box 352)
  06300275
  Education -- Ghana; Williams, Peter, 1935 Apr. 7-
- Educational planning assignment in Kenya June 1966-June 1968: Terminal report to Ford Foundation (Reports 008294) (Box 352)
  Education -- Kenya; Williams, Peter, 1935 Apr. 7-
- Report on a visit to Knoxville College, Knoxville, Tennessee, May 12-13 (Reports 008295), 1966 (Box 352)
  06400361
  Black universities; Education -- Black; Stern, Milton R.
- Appalshop (Reports 008296), 1975 (Box 352)
  07600562
  Documentaries -- Southern; Kenas, Peggy; Ford Foundation. Education and Research
- Appalshop, Inc.: film distribution (Reports 008297), 1975 (Box 352)
  Documentaries -- Southern; Kenas, Peggy
- Report on education project: first half of (Reports 008298), 1978 (Box 352)
  Documentary films -- Appalachian Region; Education -- Appalachian Region; Educational assistance -- Appalachian Region; Kenas, Peggy; Ford Foundation. Education and Research
- Appalshop: first year of Ford Grant (Reports 008299), undated (Box 352)
- The Just Community Project: final phase (Reports 008300), 1980 (Box 352)
  07600563
  Public schools; Education, Secondary; Community development; Franz, Sharon L.
- Harvard University the Just Community Project: an interim assessment (Reports 008301), 1978 (Box 352)
  Public schools; Education, Secondary; Community development -- Harvard University; Franz, Sharon L.
- Report on site visit to Lilian Webber's Project (Reports 008302), 1971 (Box 352)
  07200049
  Research Foundation Of The City University Of New York (CUNY)
  Education -- Experimental methods; Open classroom; Sealey, Leonard; Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY)
- The Center on Information on America (Reports 008303), 1978 (Box 352)
  07700352
  Educational publications; Information dissemination; Franz, Sharon L.; Center on Information on America
- Evaluation of the Educational Broadcasting Corporation Independence Fund Programming projects for the Ford Foundation (Reports 008304), 1979 (Box 352)
  07400343
  Public broadcasting; Television in education; Spergel, Howard K.; WNET (Television station: New York, N.Y.)
- Research project - Indian Law Institute - some comments (Reports 008305), 1962 (Box 352)
  Overseas Division/Near East and Africa;Asia/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  05300003
  The Indian Law Institute
  Educational law and legislation; Friedmann, Wolfgang, 1907-1972; Indian Law Institute
- Final report: "Electric Company" and second graders watching behavior (Reports 008306), 1972 (Box 352)
  07100088
  Television in education; Public broadcasting; Popp, Helen M. (Helen Mitchell), 1928-; Children's Television Workshop
- Short reflections on the Indian Law Institute (Reports 008307), 1970 (Box 352)
  International Training and Research/Overseas Division
  PA65-16.
  Education; Universities and colleges -- Law and legislation; Jackson, John H. (John Howard), 1932-; The Indian Law Institute
- Education in Argentina, November 13-December 3 (Reports 008308), 1966 (Box 352)
  International Division/Latin America
  06200031
  Education -- Argentina; Educational assistance -- Argentina; Hunter, John M. (John Merlin), 1921-
- The Institute of Economic Research of the University of Cordoba, Argentina (Reports 008309), 1961 (Box 352)
  Economics -- Research -- Argentina -- University of Cordoba; Grinṿald, Joseph
- University education and the regional concept in Central America (Reports 008310), 1963 (Box 352)
  06200109
  52 p. + appendix.
  Education -- Central America; Universities and colleges -- Central America; Enarson, Harold L., 1919-2006
- University education in Central America (Reports 008311), 1961 (Box 352)
  A report on five universities in Central America and the regional agency they created to help the Ford Foundation explore grantmaking for higher education in Central America.
  80 p.
  Education -- Central America; Universities and colleges -- Central America; University cooperation -- South America; Enarson, Harold L., 1919-2006; Universidad de Costa Rica; Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Honduras; Universidad de El Salvador; Universidad de San Carlos de Guatemala; Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua
- Preliminary report on investigation in Jamaican primary schools, November-December 1963 (Reports 008312), 1964 (Box 352)
  The objects of the investigation were to develop suitable techniques of surveying and to obtain preliminary results on the difference between Jamaican boys and boys of the same age in technological cultures on a varied battery of tests.
  Overseas Division/Latin America;Latin America and the Caribbean/Mexico and Central America;Office of the Vice President
  06200334
  The University of the West Indies
  Education, Primary -- Cross-cultural studies; Education, Primary -- Jamaica; Boys -- Jamaica; Boys -- Cross-cultural studies; Vernon, Philip E., 1905-1987; University of the West Indies
- Report on the Institute of Education, University of the West Indies (Reports 008313), 1968 (Box 352)
  Education, Higher -- West Indies; Simons, Hans; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica). Institute of Education
- Educational television in India (Reports 008314), 1966 (Box 352)
  Describes the Delhi School Television Project in its fourth year of operation.
  International Division/South and Southeast Asia;Asia/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  06000334
  224 p.
  Television in education -- India; Neurath, Paul Martin, 1911-; India
- The Delhi School Television Project: Evaluation report (Reports 008315), 1962 (Box 353)
  Based on evaluation survey of a Foundation grant to conduct an experiment in the use of television in the higher secondary schools in Delhi.
- Planning and Development Division in Ministry of Education, Pakistan (Reports 008316), 1961 (Box 353)
  Report of a grant for consultants within the Ministry of Education.
  06000374
  Educational planning -- Pakistan; Pakistan. Central Bureau of Education
- Report on consultation activities in Pakistan (Reports 008317), 1961 (Box 353)
  Report of a consultant on engineering education to the Government of Pakistan.
  Engineering -- Study and teaching -- Pakistan; Stelson, Thomas E. (Thomas Eugene), 1928-2005; Pakistan
- Governmental structures, tax capacities and other factors affecting the ability of nine states to administer block grants (Reports 008318), 1982 (Box 353)
  Supplement to Logue Report #007573.
  Block grants; States -- Administration; Logue, Frank, 1963-
- Latin American University Libraries and the Ford Foundation (Reports 008319), 1962 (Box 353)
  Academic libraries -- Latin America; Fraenkel, Peter
- Potentialities for library cooperation in Valparaiso and Vina Del (Reports 008320), 1965 (Box 353)
  Libraries -- Latin America; Barrett, Laurence N.; Ford Foundation. Latin America and Caribbean
- Developing country programs FY1983 program reviews: Rapporteur notes (Reports 008321), 1982; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Program review -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Developing Countries.
- Evaluation study: the Ford Foundation Program for Administrative Interns (Reports 008322), undated (Box 353)
  06200406
  Education -- Administration; Arts -- Management; Foster, David I.
- Report on Family Planning Program in Pakistan: 1/21/ (Reports 008323), 1966 (Box 353)
  06300038
  Population -- Pakistan -- Contraception -- Pakistan; Dixon, M. S.; Keeney, Sam
- Family Planning Program in Pakistan: final report (Reports 008324), 1966 (Box 353)
  Birth control -- Pakistan; Population assistance -- Pakistan; Dixon, M. S.; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Pakistan: log notes (Reports 008325), 1967 (Box 353)
  Birth control -- Pakistan; Population assistance -- Pakistan; Perkin, Gordon W.; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Report to the Ford Foundation and the government of Pakistan from the Population Council on the Ford Foundation Grant in Family Planning to the Government of Pakistan, 1961 and (Reports 008326), 1962 (Box 353)
  Birth control -- Pakistan; Population assistance -- Pakistan; Population Council; Population Council
- Terminal evaluation of reproductive biology grants: PA# 62-469, 470, 471, 472, 63-391, 392, 393 and 394 (Reports 008327), 1970 (Box 353)
  06200469;PA62-470;PA62-471;PA62-472;PA63-391;PA63-392;PA63-393;PA63-394.
  Population; Contraception; Sommer, John G.
- Observations on the Faculty of Agronomy: University of Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic (Reports 008328), undated (Box 353)
  06200506
  Agronomy -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Dominican Republic; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Dominican Republic; Universities and colleges -- Dominican Republic; Gamble, William K., 1920-; Universidad de Santo Domingo
- Joint Center for Urban Studies, M.I.T. and Harvard, May 18 (Reports 008329), 1961 (Box 353)
  05800391
  Education -- Urban studies; Cities and towns -- Study and teaching; Wadsworth, Homer C., 1913-1994; Joint Center for Urban Studies; Massachusetts Institute of Technology; Harvard University
- Joint Center for Urban Studies, Harvard - M.I.T., March 30 (Reports 008330), 1962 (Box 353)
  Education -- Urban studies; Cities and towns -- Study and teaching; Havighurst, Robert J. (Robert James), 1900-1991; Henderson, Julia J.; Wadsworth, Homer C., 1913-1994; Joint Center for Urban Studies; Massachusetts Institute of Technology; Harvard University
- Diagnostico de Services Espontaneous e Informales de Cuidado Infantil el los Barrios Marginales de Lima (Reports 008331), 1982 (Box 353)
  78 p.
  Children -- Peru; Anderson, Jeanine
- La Crianza y la Socializacion del Nino en LatinoAmerica Estudio de Casos: Colombia y Peru (Reports 008332), 1982 (Box 353)
  117 p.
  Child development -- Peru; Kardonsky-Titelman, Vera; Ford Foundation. Latin America and Caribbean
- Rural Family Planning Project: Allahabad Agricultural Institute (Reports 008333), 1975 (Box 353)
  Population Programulation program/European and International Affairs
  07400147
  Rural development; Birth control -- India; Friedman, Herbert L.
- The Ford Foundation and Asia (Reports 008334), 1983 (Box 353)
  Asia -- Foundation support; Ford Foundation
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008335), 1979 (Box 353)
  National Affairs/Research & Education;Rights And Social Justice Program [RSJ]; National Affairs program/Research & Education;Rights and Social Justice
  07200067
  California Center For Law In The Public Interest
  Public interest law; Rabin, Robert L.; Center for Law in the Public Interest
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008336), 1979 (Box 353)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008337), 1978 (Box 353)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008338), 1978 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008339), 1978 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008340), 1978 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008341), 1977 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008342), 1977 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008343), 1977 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008344), 1977 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008345), 1976 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008346), 1976 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008347), 1976 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008348), 1976 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008349), 1975 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008350), 1975 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008351), 1975 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008352), 1975 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008353), 1974 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008354), 1973 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008355), 1973 (Box 354)
- Monitoring report on the Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008356), 1973 (Box 354)
- Evaluation of Center for Law in the Public Interest. Third monitoring report, Feb. 5 (Reports 008357), 1973 (Box 354)
  Report based on visit to Los Angeles offices of the Center for Law in the Public Interest.
  Public interest law; Rabin, Robert L.; Center For Law In The Public Interest
- Evaluation of Center for Law in the Public Interest. Second monitoring report, Oct. 17 (Reports 008358), 1972 (Box 354)
- First report: Center for Law in the Public Interest (Reports 008359), 1972 (Box 354)
- The pilot project for Favela schools in Rio de Janeiro (State of Guanabara) (Reports 008360), 1963 (Box 354)
  "Summary report, August 1962-February 1963." --p. [1].
  16 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Education -- Brazil -- Rio de Janeiro (Brazil); Education -- Social aspects -- Brazil -- Rio de Janeiro (Brazil); Educational assistance -- Brazil; Havighurst, Robert J. (Robert James), 1900-1991; Ford Foundation. Brazil Office
- Evaluation of Ford Foundation Grant to National University of Nicaragua: Report to visit (Reports 008361), 1965 (Box 354)
  06200518
  National University Of Nicaragua
  Education, Higher -- Nicaragua; King, Richard G., 1922-; Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua
- The Three Year Master's Program at Florida State University: report on visit (Reports 008362), 1966 (Box 354)
  Education -- Arizona, University; Master's programs -- Arizona, University; Parker, Thomas W.
- Report of visit to India (Reports 008363), 1971 (Box 354)
  Purpose of the visit was to attend a Case Work Shop organized by the Administrative Staff College, Hyderabad and to explain to the people in the Indian Institute of Public Administration the purpose and intent of above note project and to explore the poss
  International Division/Population Program;Asia/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  07100180
  University Of North Carolina
  7 p. + appendix.
  Birth control -- India; Jain, Sagar C.; University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill
- Review note on the basic development plan for the Calcutta Metropolitan District (Reports 008364), 1967 (Box 354)
  Reviews and evaluates the rationale for several key aspects of the plan and suggests areas of work which call for major concentrations of effort.
  06100217
  Government Of West Bengal
  City planning -- India -- Calcutta (India); Herbert, John D.; Calcutta Metropolitan Planning Project
- Policy and personnel projections for the Ford Foundation's Calcutta Metropolitan Planning Project (Reports 008365), 1965 (Box 354)
  Memo on the Calcutta Metropolitan Planning Project.
  City planning -- India -- Calcutta (India); Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989; Metropolitan Planning Project
- Observations on Calcutta Planning Operations after visit May 19-June 2 (Reports 008366), 1963 (Box 354)
  General report of observations on the Calcutta Metropolitan Planning Operation based on a very brief visit.
  City planning -- India -- Calcutta (India); Andrade, C. Preston, 1912-1978; Ford Foundation. Metropolitan Planning Project
- The Three Year Master's Program at the University of Virginia: report on visit April 28-29 (Reports 008367), 1966 (Box 354)
  06300383
  Education -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Parker, Thomas W.; University of Virginia
- The Three Year Masters Program at the University of Wyoming: report on visit, December 6 (Reports 008368), 1966 (Box 354)
  06300384
  Universities and colleges -- Wyoming -- Graduate work; Education, Higher -- Wyoming; Parker, Thomas W.; University of Wyoming
- Report on Three-Year Master's Degree Program: University of Wyoming (Reports 008369), 1966 (Box 354)
  Universities and colleges -- Wyoming -- Graduate work; Education, Higher -- Wyoming; Carmichael, Oliver C. (Oliver Cromwell), 1891-1966; University of Wyoming
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: human rights and governance (Reports 008370), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Human rights -- Developing countries; Political science -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Human Rights and Governance
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: Andean Region and Southern Cone (Reports 008371), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  70 p.
  Ford Foundation; Technical assistance -- South America; Endowments -- South America -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Andean Region and Southern Cone
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: Bangladesh (Reports 008372), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Technical assistance -- Bangladesh; Endowments -- Bangladesh -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: Brazil (Reports 008373), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  66 p.
  Technical assistance -- Brazil; Endowments -- Brazil -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: China and other Asia (Reports 008374), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Technical assistance -- China; Endowments -- China -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: Eastern and Southern Africa (Reports 008375), Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Technical assistance -- Africa, East; Technical assistance -- Africa, Southern; Endowments -- Africa, East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa, Southern -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Africa, East -- Program evaluation; Ford Foundation. Africa, Southern -- Program evaluation
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: India, Nepal, Sri Lanka (Reports 008376), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  69 p.
  Technical assistance -- India; Technical assistance -- Nepal; Technical assistance -- Sri Lanka; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Nepal -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Sri Lanka -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: New York: International Affairs (Reports 008377), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Developing Countries Program/International Affairs
  International relations; Endowments -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. International Affairs
- Investment update (Reports 008378), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Developing Country Programs.
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: Mexico and Central America (Reports 008379), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Technical assistance -- Mexico; Technical assistance -- Central America; Endowments -- Mexico -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Central America -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: Middle East and North Africa (Reports 008380), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa, North; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa, North -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Developing Country Programs
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: Rural Poverty and Resources (Reports 008381), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Developing Countries Program/Rural Poverty and Resources
  Rural development; Technical assistance; Endowments -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Rural Poverty and Resources
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: South Africa, other Africa (regional), Israel (Reports 008382), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Developing Country Programs [Developing Countries Program];Developing Countries Program
  Technical assistance -- Africa; Technical assistance -- Israel; Endowments -- Africa -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Israel -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Africa -- Program evaluation; Ford Foundation
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: Southeast Asia (Reports 008383), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Technical assistance -- Southeast Asia; Endowments -- Southeast Asia -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation
- Developing country programs FY 1984 program reviews: West Africa (Reports 008384), 1983; Available as Microfiche only (Box 919)
  Technical assistance -- Africa, West; Endowments -- Africa, West -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Africa, West -- Program evaluation
- Final report to the Ford Foundation on the Pakistan Project (Reports 008385), 1976 (Box 354)
  06300507
  Rural development projects -- Pakistan; Rural development -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Pakistan; Niehoff, Richard O.; Comilla, Pakistan. Academy for Rural Development
- Narrative report: Comilla Project: Pakistani Academy for Rural Development, November 64 thru June 65 (Reports 008386), 1966 (Box 354)